Luke Smith

Austin, TX 78751

Phone: (510) 517-3417 | Email: <u>lucasjfsmith@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/lukesmith5120

SUMMARY

Data and information systems professional with proven background in large-scale IT project, data management, and strong programming skills in SQL, Python, Java, and JavaScript. Qualifications include identifying and implementing data-oriented goals across organizations, quickly understanding complex relational databases, and problem-solving with efficient data-driven solutions. Certifications in data analytics and visualization and specialization in supervised and unsupervised machine learning. Driven to find an opportunity to create meaningful impacts where continued learning and career development are emphasized.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, R, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, JSON, Java, C#, VBA

Tools & Libraries: Excel, Macros, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit Learn, TensorFlow, Keras, Flask, Pandas,

NumPy, PySpark, SQLAlchemy, Leaflet, Beautiful Soup, Requests, Flask, NLP, NoSQL, Regex **Applications:** GitHub, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GIT, Tableau, MVC, Looker, SFTP, Microsoft Office

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Implementation Manager Iodine Software

October 2020 – March 2023 Austin, TX

- Led over 20 technical projects working closely with hospital IT departments to implements Iodine's suite of machine learning products over a 6 14 week timeline
- Responsible for integration of millions of client data points including labs and vitals, medication, and provider documentation via the creation of a secure VPN, HL7 interfaces, and sFTP sites
- Performed in-depth data analysis, validation, and mapping efforts across client data, creating advanced SQL queries to ensure complete and successful data integration
- Enhanced medical documentation ML models by interpreting NLP engine outputs and identifying missed concepts with SQL queries utilizing regex
- Determined drivers of confidence outputs for medical evidence ML models by identifying model feature weights and cross-referencing case feature inputs
- Built and supported client-facing dashboards in Looker through interpretation of underlying SQL scripts
- Embedded and tested client single sign-on technology, such as SAML and LDAP, within Iodine application
- Mentored new Implementation Managers during and beyond project shadowing process
- Served as Level Two escalation resource for Client Success Analysts working directly with end users

Client Success Analyst Iodine Software

July 2019 – October 2020 Austin, TX

- Triaged and solved 20 to 50 technical issues reported by users per week through an in-depth understanding of Iodine application, code base, data structure, and lifecycle
- Participated in weekly data science model investigation meetings, reviewing inputs and interpreting machine learning outputs for over 50 models.
- Implemented machine learning model improvements by redesigning model escalation process to emphasize understanding, investigating, and translating client concerns to Data Science leadership
- Analyzed medical records and generated reports using SQL to support non-technical account managers
- Built and tested 20 to 30 custom indicators based on medical events using Java and XML, such as the presence of COVID-19

PROJECTS

Team Lead May 2023 – August 2023

Pro Venue Tracker | pro-venue-tracker.onrender.com | github.com/lucasjfsmith/pro-venue-tracker

- Cloud-based Flask app utilizing Leaflet.js interactive map to displays each professional sports team, venue, and next event across the MLB, NFL, NBA, NHL, and MLS
- Allows users to dynamically display leagues of their choosing and view venue and event information by clicking icons displayed on the coordinates of each venue
- Venue coordinates gathered from Kaggle.com, schedule information web-scraped from sportsreference.com, and additional information pulled from Geoapify API
- Data cleaned with pandas, posted to Postgres DB, and pulled into app with SQLAlchemy and Flask API

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Program Director Lair of the Bear

March 2018 – August 2018 Pinecrest, CA

- Managed a staff of 30, coordinating food, maintenance, entertainment, and recreation operations in remote wilderness environment
- Responsible for customer satisfaction, fielding and prioritizing issues and resources, determining possible solutions, and relaying all resolutions directly to customers
- 2018 Customer Service Award recipient

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

Explore AustinSub-Mentor

2022 – Present
Austin, TX

Available as a substitute mentor for outdoor activities with Austin youth

BORP Adaptive Sports Revolution Fundraiser

2020 – Present

Berkeley, CA

Annual bike ride fundraiser raising money for people with disabilities in the Bay Area

Data Entry Beto for Senate 2018 September 2018 – November 2018

Austin, TX

EDUCATION

Coursera

Machine Learning Specialization

July 2023 – Present

- Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification; Advance Learning Algorithms; Unsupervised Learning, Recommenders, Reinforcement Learning taught by Professor Andrew Ng of Stanford University
- Courses emphasize understanding of math and concepts underlying common algorithms like regression, clustering, decision trees, and neural networks

University of Texas at Austin

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

March 2023 – August 2023

• Six month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in VBA, Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Spark, and Machine Learning.

University of Texas at Austin BBA in Management Information Systems

2015 - 2019